<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Web Development on Pavlo&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/web-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Web Development on Pavlo&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/web-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modern Frontend Frameworks: React vs Vue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/07/16/modern-frontend-frameworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2025/07/16/modern-frontend-frameworks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The landscape of frontend development has evolved dramatically over the past decade, with modern JavaScript frameworks becoming essential tools for building interactive web applications. Among these frameworks, React and Vue have emerged as two of the most popular choices, each with its own strengths and philosophies. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll compare these frameworks and help you decide which one might be the best fit for your next project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-component-based-architecture&#34;&gt;Understanding Component-Based Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Both React and Vue are built around the concept of components, which are reusable, self-contained pieces of code that encapsulate HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. This approach offers several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modern PHP Development Practices</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/07/15/modern-php-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2025/07/15/modern-php-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PHP has evolved significantly over the years, transforming from a simple scripting language into a robust platform for web application development. With the release of PHP 8 and the adoption of modern development practices, PHP continues to be a relevant and powerful choice for web developers. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore the latest PHP development practices and tools that can help you build efficient, maintainable, and secure web applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;php-8-features-that-improve-developer-experience&#34;&gt;PHP 8 Features That Improve Developer Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PHP 8 introduced several features that significantly improve the developer experience and code quality:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/07/14/getting-started-with-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2025/07/14/getting-started-with-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most popular open-source static site generators. It&amp;rsquo;s written in Go and known for its amazing speed and flexibility. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my experience getting started with Hugo and why I chose it for my blog.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-choose-a-static-site-generator&#34;&gt;Why Choose a Static Site Generator?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Static site generators offer several advantages over traditional content management systems:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speed&lt;/strong&gt;: Static sites are incredibly fast since they don&amp;rsquo;t require server-side processing or database queries.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;: With no database or server-side scripts, there are fewer vulnerabilities to exploit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplicity&lt;/strong&gt;: The build process is straightforward, and the resulting site is just HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control&lt;/strong&gt;: All content can be stored in a Git repository, making it easy to track changes and collaborate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hosting Options&lt;/strong&gt;: Static sites can be hosted almost anywhere, often for free (GitHub Pages, Netlify, Vercel, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started-with-hugo&#34;&gt;Getting Started with Hugo&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Installing Hugo is straightforward. On macOS, you can use Homebrew:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Themes and Customization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/07/13/wordpress-themes-customization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2025/07/13/wordpress-themes-customization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress themes control the look and feel of your website. They provide the visual design and layout for your site, while also offering various functionality through built-in features and customization options. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explore the world of WordPress themes and share tips for customizing them to create a unique website.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;types-of-wordpress-themes&#34;&gt;Types of WordPress Themes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;free-themes&#34;&gt;Free Themes&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WordPress.org offers a vast repository of free themes that you can install directly from your WordPress dashboard. These themes are reviewed by the WordPress team to ensure they meet quality standards and security requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
